GRAEME HADDOW

• DETAILS •

Stirling, United Kingdom 07595841691 graeme@haddow64.com

• LINKS •

haddow64.com

o SKILLS o

C#

.NET

ASP.NET

ASP.NET MVC

Web API

Razor

Blazor

Entity Framework

Azure

AWS

Java

Spring & Spring Boot

Gradle

SQL

JavaScript

jQuery

TypeScript

React

HTML

CSS

C++

Microservices

Docker

Linux

Cypress

Git

GitLab CI

Jenkins

PROFILE

Skilled and motivated senior software engineer with experience in the full software development life cycle.

A wide experience in multiple full stack environments including C# .NET and Java/Spring, using these technologies to deliver multiple enterprise level high volume systems. Committed to delivering great quality software and constantly learning new tools and technologies.

■ EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Senior Software Engineer at BT

October 2017 — Present

- Wrote and delivered a system using C# .NET5 running under Docker for Linux to process Microsoft Teams telephony and location data to keep the emergency services database updated.
- Lead the design and development of a set of common microservice components
 and user portals based on Docker and written in Java with Spring Boot to unify
 and simplify asset management within the organisation. This brought together
 what was previously a series of disparate systems and processes and built them
 on a common technology increasing efficiency and money saving measures.
- Development of a series of Web API in Spring systems to handle back-end processing of all IT and system access orders across the company.

Software Engineer at BT

January 2016 — October 2017

- Delivered a C# ASP.NET MVC system to track and recover SQL server licenses that were no longer needed.
- Implemented a site written in C# with various Web API endpoints to onboard EE employees to the BT Active Directory domain after their acquisition by BT.
- Maintained a legacy classic ASP system to deal with the refresh and disposal of computing assets. Implemented TDD with NUnit to minimise risk of regression issues of the legacy system.

IT Support Manager at BT

August 2011 — January 2016

- Support of various editions of Windows Server (including Active Directory and Exchange server support).
- Developed a series of C# WinForms applications to standardize note taking, automate work logging and asset tracking. Delivering savings and increased revenue of over £72,000 P/A.

EDUCATION

AWS - Solutions Architect, The Open University

2022

12-week course covering the content of the AWS Certified Solutions Architect. It covered modules in S3 storage, EC2, AWS Networking, AWS CLI and API, Microservices, AWS Lambda, as well as best practices in architecting cloud-based systems.

BSc (Hons) Computer Games Technology, University of Abertay Dundee

2006 - 2011

The undergraduate course focused not only upon game programming skills, but the skills required to become a well-rounded programmer with modules in agile development, network programming and mathematics as well as core modules in C++ programming.